[SPEAKER_00] Hello. Hey, Nate. How are you? I'm good. How are you? I'm doing well. I'm hanging in there, all things considered.
[SPEAKER_01] Give me two seconds to set up my camera. It's plugged in, but it's just not detecting it.
[SPEAKER_00] No worries. And just so you know, I've had the meeting on auto -transcribed, so everything we're saying right now is being transcribed, just so you're aware. But that's all for me and research purposes down the line. Of course. Thanks for doing this. I mean, a thousand thanks. You're actually the first student I'm interviewing, so. Yay.
[SPEAKER_01] I read over the form. It seems really cool. I can't wait to hear more about it.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, absolutely. We'll get into it.
[SPEAKER_01] Trying to get this video camera to work. There we go. Settings.
[SPEAKER_00] gonna post uh something in the chat for you this is called a question menu um and i don't know how many interviews you've done in the past i know that you had that mic so that you you on some level are familiar with the process uh at least on a live streaming level um but uh here is a question menu nate there's nate there we go i'm so glad you got the job by the way thank you That's such a such a success. I mean, so that happened the day after the reference letter came in.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, yeah, it was. I think they were moving forward with it. The references were kind of a kind of a formality, it seemed.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, I was I was making sure that, you know, even if there was a formality that you got the job you deserve. So I'm glad I really
[SPEAKER_01] appreciate it. Thank
[SPEAKER_00] you so much for doing that. Yeah, it's my pleasure. So I. posted in the chat uh an interview question menu yes i just opened it up very cool right here i love the mic it looks great thank you thank you uh so uh yeah and i'm just gonna like read from this uh So question menus designed and this is this is recent, recent discovery of mine. And I always thought that any interview I've done, I'm kind of always nervous about the fixed linear sequence that interview that the questions come in. And I think this gives you an opportunity to go through it kind of step by step and to choose whichever questions are most relevant to your experience, because I think. CUNY students, my hypothesis is use CUNY Reddit and Discord for a variety of reasons. And that's what I'm really trying to pin down. So I don't want to, you know, close off on those opportunities for, you know, self -directed responses. And that's what the question menu is there for.
[SPEAKER_01] So I just get to pick like one from each category?
[SPEAKER_00] yeah yeah you can you can pick one you can kind of like pick one and a half you know you can address one that maybe relates to another really just uh kind of whatever responses it sparks in you um but uh yeah as a general guideline one one question uh is a it's a good start So, yeah, and I mean, I think before even we get started on that, just tell me a little bit about yourself, Nate. I think in a way that is not maybe represented in the teaching and learning context, you know, your experience at CSUNY and, you know, how we, you know, came to be here today.
[SPEAKER_01] Sounds good. Hi, I am Nate. I was a CCNY student for three and a half years. I just graduated. I have my ceremony coming up. I was originally, I was born in New York. I lived there for quite a few years. I moved away for high school because of my parents had jobs elsewhere. And then when I graduated high school, I wanted to go back to New York and I chose, that's where I spent my college career.
[SPEAKER_00] Amazing. Hey, and congrats on the ceremony coming up.
[SPEAKER_01] Thank you. I'm really excited.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, you should be. Be excited about it. You only get one.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] Unless you go
[SPEAKER_01] to more higher
[SPEAKER_00] education. Well, that's true. Yeah, I mean, I'm hoping to have one after all of this is done myself. Yeah, I'm hopeful. But they never change. I'll say that much. Yeah, they're always a lot of names. Yep, exactly. A lot of paper, a lot of names. Yeah. But just kind of moving forward, you know, so platform experiences, and I've kind of structured this so that we can really start with any of these categories. But platform experiences, I think just because I'm interested in how you first came to discover Reddit or Discord just as a user, as well as, you know, as a kind of underground resource for CUNY students in many ways, almost like access to the meta of surviving at CUNY. So how did you first kind of encounter that?
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, so as a personal user of Reddit and Discord, I started using it, I think, a long time ago. My friends got me into it for playing video games. But for CUNY, I found a lot of organization through Discord was personal for students. A lot of classes, someone would make a Discord and share the link to everyone. It was either that or WhatsApp. There were some teachers who utilized it, but I think there was a lot of also student organization. And for Reddit, I think you kind of touched on this, but it's a lot more of a useful resource. You get to learn a lot about what's actually going on with a lot of programs. So for me specifically, I did an internship my junior year. And I forget the exact name, but I learned a lot about it through the... the CUNY Reddit, where other people were sharing their experiences. There was a long interview process for this internship, and people kind of shared what the group interview process was like and gave me an idea of that and what the kind of trajectory of this was going to be on a more personal level than the web pages that CUNY provided about it that were very professional and didn't provide the same amount of info. And I think there's a lot of cases like that where the student -led Reddit lets people be a lot more honest with their assessment of CUNY programs or classes or teachers or, you know, the universities as a whole.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, I mean, that's a great, that's a great answer. And I think an exemplary one where you kind of get access to the, you know, there's The boss text, which is the, you know, the CUNY web page. And then there's the hidden curriculum, which are all the stuff that they don't tell you you need to know, but that you discover along the way, one way or another through, I think, these resources. So that's great. And OK, I think, you know, let me let me look at these other questions here. I think you answered them brilliantly. So, I mean, OK, so that's how you encountered CUNY Discord and Reddit. And if you want to lean into one or the other, you don't feel like obliged to both Discord and Reddit, depending on how these interviews pan out. I may just do one because it's a giant ecosystem. How does your use of, let's say, CUNY Reddit evolved since you first discovered it for those purposes?
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah. So I think originally I was more of like a service level user, kind of like scanning posts. It was more of like, let's see what's going on. Maybe people will mention events and stuff. Right. But I think as I went through my years at CUNY, I started to develop a more kind of targeted approach to using the Reddit. It was more like. if I'm taking this class, has anyone said that this professor is awful and doesn't remember to grade your papers? Or has anyone mentioned that this professor is really good and like provides great feedback and reference letters and is very useful? Or with programs, like does this program provide, you know, help and is actually meaningful? And there would be a lot of honest conversations about that on the Reddit. So I think as my time at CUNY progressed, it was more of like, Less surface level, just like, let's see what's going on and more. Let's check that what I'm doing is worth doing according to the other people on this page.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, yeah. So I and I almost see like, you know, you're almost dividing it into like access to the main, the, you know, the, the mainstream, you know, public discourse that comes out of the kind of surrounds the college experience, like what's going on at CCNY, right? And that on the one hand, and then on the other hand, you have, you know, at like this purpose driven use of it, where you need information, and information that isn't going to be publicized. a CUNY webpage. And you needed to be real and down to earth. I just, I respect that. I mean, I think that that's my experience going through the academic grinder all these years. But yeah, that's awesome. Great. Thanks, Nate. So let's move forward. Let's keep going. Community and support. So you mentioned the authenticity, the honesty, the forthrightness, the tendency for, you know, commentary in Reddit, but maybe also Discord to be to be pretty straightforward and grounded. And I'm curious, to what extent do you think that that has to do with the pseudonymous? or anonymous kind of design of these platforms where your identity is always kind of by the, at the first stage, you know, the first step, you're forced to make a username and to stick with it on Reddit. And I'm just curious, do you think that that, because the university doesn't really have a mean by which to enable that, that people flock to Reddit and Discord, or is it more about the platforms and the kind of subculture of it all?
[SPEAKER_01] So I think that it's more prevalent on Reddit than on Discord. This is, I guess, a little bit of a tangent. I think that Discord can be a little less like... Anonymous. I think a lot of times Discord accounts, especially because there were a lot of Discord users at CUNY who were using it purely for educational purposes. It was a little less. It was more everybody's name. I know I had one class where there was a bit of a debacle with someone sharing answers in a Discord and the teacher was secretly in the Discord and saw that the student had shared the answers and then... That student got in trouble. So there are, I think, more situations like that on Discord where they're on a class -by -class basis. And the larger CUNY Discords... are moderated by cuny um for the most part so i think i found that reddit was more of that place where there was an anonymousness of not sharing like answers or stuff but sharing sharing information that would be a little more restricted and not talked about and people had this freedom to kind of share their opinions unfiltered about cuny systems and cuny programs so
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah. So, I mean, this is actually news to me. So the major CUNY discords are, I mean, do they have official administrative staff or are those like who's governing those from your side of things? Because, yeah, go ahead.
[SPEAKER_01] yeah so i think it depends because i um for example the first semester that i was at cuny i was in the cuny dorms and that was ran by the ras and some more administrative staff and had some stuff like that the larger cuny discord has student mods but then i believe it also has a uh an administrator but then on like a class by class level as you break it down like i had an intro to theater arts class where the teacher had a discord for everything and that was just ran by the teacher and was uh very community based and people would kind of share their thoughts more freely so i i think it really does depend and i i like the situation i mentioned i think sometimes students got comfortable with this idea that it's just students and like it's kind of more of a free like private situation when you know the teacher got the link and joined the class and it's like being monitored in a way that they don't realize so i think there's a little little bit less freedom on discord than on on reddit where like you said you pick a username you stick with it and it is much more anonymous most reddit accounts are not tied to the exact person what some are though some people do tie it
[SPEAKER_00] I made that mistake. The first Reddit that I ever made, I did Zmull, which was like my username. You know, it's enough distance from my full name, but it's enough to dox me. So and that's the question here is getting doxed in these private spaces, especially like a Discord server that's designed to be private as opposed to the community ones, which are designed to be public. And yeah, an instructor kind of doing pedagogical espionages. is alarming. That's a fantastic anecdote. And I'm sure that happens more often than folks like, even researchers like me even think.
[SPEAKER_01] I think the difference too is that sometimes discards get categorized as private spaces, whereas a Reddit is almost always categorized as a public space, like a space where anyone can view what you're saying. So even though you're maybe writing it in a more open way, you know that anyone could see this. So either, you know, personal details are a little more restricted or you're just aware that this should be more of a communal conversation than a discord where stuff can kind of be treated like
[SPEAKER_00] DMs. Yeah. I mean, the code of conduct on Reddit, for instance. And by the way, it's fine if we go off book from the questions. They're semi -structured interviews. It's meant to be a conversation. Like, I care more about free associating than anything. But I think, yeah, it seems as though the code of conduct, both the explicit one that gets assigned to the CUNY Reddit subreddits and the kind of implicit, you know, the agreement that everybody makes when they contribute to the Reddit is perhaps. maybe more uh um fulfilled on reddit than it is on discord where it gets blurry depending on if it's a private or public server um do you have any other i mean anecdotes are are great that that's really what i'm interested in um yeah i
[SPEAKER_01] guess not specifically i mean i've had some really great classroom discords i will say like i mean for our class we had a great community -led discord but i think a lot of teachers have embraced it and made like responses through discord and stuff but also given space for students to communicate and then i find that the ones that are purely student -led can sometimes devolve a little bit yeah um i've had i've had several i'm like looking at them as we speak but i've had several uh uh just purely student classroom -led discords that are a little bit more like someone posting do you have the answers to question three four and five and then not responding or talking about homeworks which can be really helpful like open student discussion about it but i've always found those to be a little bit less uh participatory yeah by people they're just a little more closed off than than reddit which i i'm a pretty passive user of reddit i don't really post on it too much i kind of i kind of use it as a resource because i find that it has some really good information um But I have asked a few questions, but I'm more of like an observer on Reddit, so I don't have as many antidotes.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, I mean, that's fine. That's fine. Yeah, I mean, I think I'm more of a lurker, right? Like I read, same with these discords. And I sometimes feel like I'm like an actual like lurker when I'm in the Cooney discords. I'm not part of the private ones with students, obviously, because I was an instructor. But, you know, I always think it's interesting to consider the, you know, the vast unknown of all the private discord servers that are created alongside classes. so pointing that out um and so like on the on the subject of of reddit you're so you're uh you're a passive user you read it uh more than you you write within it uh do you upvote downvote uh because that's a kind of participation too yeah
[SPEAKER_01] i think i do sometimes like uh for example i remember when i got my um my internship i i was really stressed because it was like it was like um we had a group interview where we had to do something and it was, there was like no details about it, but they were doing different blocks for these interviews. And I remember someone who was in the first block posted a full description of what we were going to be doing. And so, I mean, it let me get some extra preparation that the interviewers probably didn't want, but I was, I was thankful for the, for the information. So I think I did upload a post like that, but most of the time, if someone mentions like a. you know, an event going on on campus or like some very some more like general information. I don't interact really at all.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That feels more like an email almost. Right. You know, exactly. And that's that's an interesting line that's that's blurred here. And especially when you think when you think about how students kind of are at the. have to cross these boundaries between sending emails to professors and operating within these Discord servers or messaging on Reddit. There's such slight differences, yet so many similarities. Do you find that you do a lot of reading in the Discords or are you more participatory in those?
[SPEAKER_01] So I think it depends on the environment. For the very big CUNY ones, I don't really say much. I'll like I'll check for the the big posts in the community discord of people talking about, you know, the events channel, which I don't even think I have, you know, the ability to post in. And there's there's obviously there's like there's smaller channels that are for everyone to talk in. But I don't I don't find myself talking unless I have something, you know, important to say, which is fairly uncommon.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, I mean, I'm not a big poster. I find myself very much aligned with you in these ways. I mean, if there's moments where I feel like it's almost incumbent upon me to say something, then maybe so. I
[SPEAKER_01] often find myself saying something if I want to correct a piece of info. There's been a few times where someone has said something that I know is wrong or they say this is the time of something and it's actually something else. I'll say, I think this is actually this time. because I don't want there to be misinformation, but I don't find myself going out of the way to say these things.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, you're not a Wikipedia editor out there, but that's a really fascinating point because you're serving as a kind of passive fact checker and gathering information for yourself, which begs the question, how do you differentiate good content, good news from bad news in these subreddits? That
[SPEAKER_01] is a good question because that is tough. There are definitely times where I've read something and believed it and then later found out that it was... incorrect in some way yeah um i kind of is a general vibe check there's not much like fact checking that goes into it like i kind of i'll read that an event is happening and i'll generally believe it because i don't believe on these student -led discords that people have too much incentive to lie i think for the most part the info is coming from a place of honesty and any any anything that's wrong about it is is not from a place of um misintent but more just mistaken uh fact so yeah yeah i i generally trust it and i think i maybe someone's posted like 11 a .m instead of you know 12 a .m but it's generally harmless not
[SPEAKER_00] disinformation it might be misinformation far more harmless yeah but yeah are you more likely to trust uh posts that are made within the uh um and in cooney subreddits um compared to the broader reddit ecosystem
[SPEAKER_01] That is a good question. I think yes, I think especially because it's like it's student led and like general Reddit can be kind of a crapshoot. Yeah, it can be, you know, a very interesting ecosystem of people saying stuff that I don't usually like to interact with general Reddits because I can find I find them pretty. pretty taxing and toxic. But I think that the CUNY ecosystem specifically, since it's all students who are all participating in this, there's not really any malicious actors, for the most part, I find.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, I mean, to the contrary, I think one of the most common posts that I often see involve students asking their peers if something is spam. And so I think that many students seem to flock to the CUNY subreddits almost as a safe refuge from the wild west of the web. But then there's the question of moderation and governance. How much do you know about how, let's say, the... I'm not sure about the servers. I've already asked a little bit about that. But the CUNY subreddits like the CCNY, did you ever take an interest in the people who were kind of like setting the rules of engagement?
[SPEAKER_01] No, now that you say it, I've never really paid too much mind to the moderation of these subreddits. I don't know if they're student -led or CUNY -led. I assume they're student -led, but I don't know how that's done.
[SPEAKER_00] I think a lot of them are alumni. Oh, okay. Kind of, yeah, good Samaritans maybe. But there's controversy during the pandemic. There was a Splinter subreddit where the Cooney Uncensored is what it's called. That came as a result of one of the moderators who governed the CUNY subreddit during the pandemic had controversial moderation practices, according to the Splinter subreddit. The Splinter subreddit never really took off. It never developed that critical mass and that energy that kind of carries these subreddits forward. Very
[SPEAKER_01] interesting.
[SPEAKER_00] An interesting, yeah, an interesting kind of fracture in these community, these student communities. in the ways that they negotiate their own circulation of discourse. I mean, that's one of the reasons I'm interested in it. I can't find another point in the history of universities where there's been a clear or at least semi -clear digital town square that you can go and read things. But anyway, yeah, any thoughts on that?
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, I think that's very interesting because, I mean, I know there has been, I have heard of, of controversies happening in these subreddits i remember when there was the encampment on campus right uh there was a lot of conversation between pro and pro -palestine pro -israel um people talking about like the thing i usually don't engage with that stuff i'm i'm using it more as a town square of information about like events and class specific stuff i use it more uh directly for myself i don't find myself that much of a general browser of it it's kind of like if i'm seeking a piece of info i feel that i can get a more honest answer from reddit but i don't use it in the way that a lot of people do as a as a community building which i think it's really great for it's just not the way that i ever used it yeah
[SPEAKER_00] i mean same here even like i i bite my tongue i'm like doing an entire dissertation on it uh and i like don't find a lot of community myself but i see you know it's it's hard not to see it
[SPEAKER_01] yeah
[SPEAKER_00] looking at cuny reddit and instructors slowly figuring out that they can uh that they can search their names in the cuny reddit and it's a kind of similar experience is going to check you rate my professor yep it's very similar
[SPEAKER_01] very similar except with more personal stories
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, yeah, which I think is, it grounds it more, right? Do you, do you notice any, like, conventions? I think, I think we may, we may not, in my other writing classes, we talk about discourse conventions. You see it all the time with programming, but like, you know, with those implicit rules, or, you know, common, like, genres of posts, almost, you know, the rate my schedule is one of them. Yeah. Is this spam? Is another kind of like low -key one? Do any others come to mind when I like note that? There's a lot of
[SPEAKER_01] talk about the escalators. That's a big one. The escalators being out is a huge one. I think we touched on the talking about people's professors. Yeah, yeah. There's obviously events. But yeah, there's a lot of like Reddit -specific conventions that you kind of don't think about. But it's like, you know, the way the posts are structured is very Reddit. It's kind of hard to articulate, but... Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, it's
[SPEAKER_01] definitely there.
[SPEAKER_00] Let's sit with that, though, because I'm trying to articulate it myself. One comparison I've heard, and I wonder if this rings true, is that Reddit kind of serves as the help column or the advice column in newspapers. Yeah,
[SPEAKER_01] it does feel very newspaper -y or like... Like you said, town square, but it's like this communal kind of like... old days of the internet like forum boards a little more organized than those but it's like it has that feeling of just these disparate people communicating that i feel like a lot of other reddits kind of lose i mean not all reddits depends on the size right but if when you're looking at big stuff it's very much uh condensed and it's so fast and you're not really recognizing these people but there will be like trends among cuny reddits because it's a much smaller community that you'll see like these repeat posters or these like these common threads like like rate my schedule or like the escalators being out or is this spam and and it creates this this more communal feeling than you get from other reddits i think i think because of size and because of the demographic being focused on students who are all using this information all using this information for similar reasons. A lot of reddits are more for building community, but I think the community reddit has this interesting like dichotomy between people who are using this for community and people who are using this for info gathering and like finding out what's going on honestly without having to go through like, you know, the professionalism that you'll find through other information sources.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah. Well said. Well said. Or, yeah, going and reading it on the bathroom walls. Yeah. I'll give you I'll give you a second because I know interviews can be really taxing. But this is I'm learning so much that it's like that grounded. This is really what we're driving for. Right. You know, that grounded lived experience that is hard. You know, it's hard to make up misinformation about your feelings and experiences in a class. It doesn't really exist in that space. I think there's also less incentive
[SPEAKER_01] to make stuff up. I mean, like in a lot of Reddits, people make up stuff for attention, which I mean, obviously could be a motivator for CUNY subreddits. But the way the Reddit is used kind of disincentivizes that misinformation because it's... it's more you'd get more bang for your buck doing it on in a bigger place so unless you have some specific qualm with cuny there's not really a reason to use the subreddit in that way as much even though it definitely happens yeah
[SPEAKER_00] no i think that's a really i think that's a really perceptive point um you know and yeah there's less reason to troll because you're going to get less reactions um yeah scrolling is all about the reactions yeah and uh You know, it reminds me, because so much of like internet culture and digital culture more broadly is, you know, we've been discussing it. I'm curious about, you know, the... the connection between like the internet, the web of old and the web of new and, and Reddit seems to, uh, maintain like this, uh, on, you know, unprecedented consistency over the years. Um, they haven't really, I mean, they changed their homepage one time, uh, and it was initially just like, uh, you know, uh, bookmark social bookmarking. Um, and now these communities have sprouted up at multiple scales. Um, I'm, uh, I'm curious if you find. particular value in the way that the discussion forums are structured? Is it something about the way that posting and commenting is designed? Is it the upvotes and the ranking system? What differentiates Reddit, in your mind, from other social media? I
[SPEAKER_01] think you touched on a really good point there in that question that Reddit is very much a bridge from the old days of the internet to the new days of the internet. It's very much a modernization of these old forum boards. I mean, I was very big into video games my whole life. So there used to be this time when forum boards were king. And if you had a question, you couldn't Google anything. What you had to do is you had to search. forum boards and try to find someone who'd ask the same question or if you couldn't find anything ask it yourself like how to beat a level or something and reddit has created that and i think for a while it became less important and reddit became more focused on community um but now if you google anything right with the prevalence of like uh ai articles and like awful articles you'll often find people searching question on reddit because you'll get a more genuine response than an article from a game journalist website that put it through three ais before they got their output or are padding for time so you scroll through as many ads as possible and just not getting to the point where if you find a reddit asking the same question it'll be very matter of fact and you'll get a lot of answers some of those answers will be the most unhelpful thing you've ever read and there'll be someone saying like oh this is so easy just google it um but it's You'll also often find really helpful and insightful answers for exactly what you're talking about and someone who went through the same problem you went through. So I think that it has kind of scaled in usefulness from just a community platform that it was, I think, when Google was at its peak usefulness. And as Google and other search engines have decreased in... conciseness or usefulness in finding your answers i think reddit's ability not just as a social media platform but as a answer finding website or even search engine has scaled in usefulness among even general users who aren't like even having a reddit account but are googling an answer on reddit and i think that the cuny discord does definitely play into that
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah. And I think that's an interesting point. It's I mean, really well said all the way through. But, you know, the fact that you can go on to Reddit without having to sign in. And that's such a fundamental difference between now X. They used to have that with Twitter. You could sign on to the Twitter ecosystem. You could you could, you know, do that without having to sign in. But of course, now that there's a barrier to entry and it changes the. the publicness and the politics of the space i think um and access to it moreover yeah
[SPEAKER_01] and i think the also the locationality of of reddit is so interesting and i mean like when you search something on twitter you can often find people dealing with the same problem in the same way but stuff isn't categorized by community which really makes reddit stick out because it creates these these ecosystems that we've been talking about that let you um Find information on a general scale. If you're searching for just kind of more information about a topic, you can go to a community and search for it. Or if you're searching for something more broadly, you can search the entire ecosystem of like all Reddit communities, which creates this difference from something like X or, you know, any other social media where people share their experiences, where it's shared on a personal level and you can look up a specific person, but you're not like looking up unless you're using hashtags, which are unbelievably. unhelpful for the most part you're not finding like the same community driven uh categorization that you do on reddit yeah
[SPEAKER_00] yeah yeah absolutely um it reminds me i mean that what comes to mind there uh and this is so rich now because the differences between x or formerly twitter and reddit i think are worth uh unpacking but just the the role of bots in in these uh um you know these platform ecosystems. On Twitter, it seems that most of the controversy, I mean, there's been a number of use for Twitter bots, but also on Reddit for a long time. And every time you sign on to a Reddit, you get a message from a bot. And there's such a difference in use and design. I'm wondering, what are your encounters with bots in the broader? reddit ecosystem um and i mean i know i don't think they use many in the cuny ones but just uh any other like additional thoughts on that front yeah
[SPEAKER_01] that's a very interesting question because i've always found reddit more helpful and less of that um i remember there was a big deal uh when they were selling the uh like api scraping stuff from reddit and there was a big deal with that and how it would affect bots and stuff but
[SPEAKER_00] their api is much more restrictive now but yeah yeah
[SPEAKER_01] i think that um i think that bots i generally see them in comments i don't usually see that many bot posts but that's because i'm using it more specifically i'm not scrolling through reddits as much as i sometimes would there's certain certain topics when i'm like interested in something uh I guess this is an example, a little off topic, but there's this game coming out called 2XKO. And I wanted to like kind of learn more. And it was in a beta phase where not everyone had access. And I kind of wanted to see what people were doing. So I remember scrolling through the Reddit, like looking at different people's discoveries and stuff. But when I'm looking for a specific answer, I'll often see bots in comments. You see a ton of that. Like, I mean, there's like the funny ones, which are like. accidental haiku detected or like you know the more malicious ones what
[SPEAKER_00] about the malicious ones do you uh what uh i i'm curious like
[SPEAKER_01] phishing links or like you know getting people to click on a malicious link is is the most common but i feel like a majority of reddits have have moderators that lock that down pretty tightly uh if you do see those it'll often be on kind of dead reddits that are not seeing any posts anymore. But you very rarely see malicious stuff because I think the community -driven aspect of it creates for this higher level of moderation. And like you said, the terms of service, what we talked about earlier, create this ecosystem where the moderators can very easily just take out these malicious things. I mean, maybe there are definitely... overzealous moderators who take out too much, but it does usually lead to a cleaner user experience of having these malicious posts taken away. Because when you're interacting and posting on a Reddit, you are agreeing to deal with the community's guidelines rather than on Twitter, where it's an open space and you can just say whatever to the ether and it can get reported and taken down, but it's not going to be the same as a community moderating what you're saying.
[SPEAKER_00] Excellent. I mean, excellent point. Wow. Like, you know, I that that's a point that I had to read in scholarship on Reddit. So well done. Yeah, I think I mean, we're really kind of fleshing out those differences. And yeah, the federated governance of these communities, the federated moderation, they don't like leave it to, you know, algorithms at scale, they leave it. People who get to use the bots for the purpose of protecting their communities. Yeah, and
[SPEAKER_01] people who are passionate, right? Like I think most Reddit moderators are very passionate about these topics, whereas on a large scale of Twitter, people aren't that passionate about getting rid of, you know, not safe for work bots or like malicious link bots. But when it's affecting your community that you feel like you've grown and you're a part of and you're a leader in, you really don't want to see those bots. hurting the community and hurting, I mean, even your status role, if we look at it from like a sociological perspective of seeing these people who feel like they have a position of power that will be minimized if these places become unsafe to talk in because of the dilution by bots, right? And you were talking about a splinter cell, like if you've been ousted from your power as a moderator, you kind of want to recreate that environment that people want to use because it gives you a sense of importance.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, right. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. And so on top of all of this, and I mean, I think we've gone above and beyond the questions that I had boiler plated here. But I'm curious if you've tried Reddit answers yet. It's in beta while you know, on April 13, I think today, I actually haven't checked recently, but over the past Last month, I've tried it a few times. But yeah, let me just ask you that. Have you tried Reddit answers before? No, I have not heard of this.
[SPEAKER_01] It's
[SPEAKER_00] like their generative AI research preview where they use the Reddit knowledge base as the transfer stand. for the model um with a simple chatbot you know input field uh and then you can ask about cuny uh subreddits for instance you could ask about financial aid or fafsa um you know you could ask about uh your schedule um and i'm wondering how you uh how you reconcile this against uh the uh the reliability and the groundedness of the information resources that you look for and find on Reddit. Do you think it's a different way of accessing that information? Because you talked about going through all these Reddits at different scales and in different levels of depth. And yeah, I'll leave it at that.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, it's kind of tough when I haven't used the tool and I don't have too much info. But I'm going to base my answer based off other generative AI that I've used. And I am a very big hater of these generative AI. summaries they can often be useful but i think specifically like copilot uh on microsoft edge summarizing your search or google i often find that to be very like i don't know it can be very useful and like i have definitely used it when i just want a quick search and like i just take what it says um but i try not to trust them and i try to verify with an actual source that i can find so i do worry about um summarization of reddits which are even less you know moderated uh i mean they're more moderated but the the answers can vary more in quality i think less on the cuny pages but more overall yeah i wouldn't want to take a summary of a lot of reddit questions i would probably want to find a specific general someone asking the same question as me and doing it i haven't used if it would let you search those that would be helpful um but i i generally don't like AI in my searching for answers. And so I think Reddit, I kind of go to it more to escape that than anything. So I'm not too interested in that personally.
[SPEAKER_00] That's, I mean, a great answer for a number of reasons, just because I think, you know, I want to be mindful of time because I'm not going to I'm not going to. No worries. I'm good to talk all day. I mean, it's great. It's it's honestly just like a fun conversation about an unusual, I think, developing, growing kind of phenomenon. But yeah, I mean, I think that I think that your responses, I mean, I think that your mentality and you. in these spaces is it tracks across like all of your answers because you were talking about triangulating resources and going to different subreddits, you know, not taking anything at face value and, you know, being just a cautious skeptic until you find the answers you need to. And generative AI is kind of this tool that allows you singular answer to a question that of course maybe has multiple. And so. Information literacy on A+. But I already knew that. I think
[SPEAKER_01] generative AI also takes away from a lot of information literacy because, I mean... For the most part, it is a summarization of a large, large, large set of data. And you can't exactly know where that info is coming from. And so for a general answer, I think they can often be helpful in summarizing a vast amount of data. But it's something that I personally never want to take at face value. I'm always reminded of when Google first rolled out their AI program and that you could search like... how to make your cheese gooier on pizza and i would say add elmer's glue because it was citing like um pr things where they would add it to make it look better for photos and stuff and so yeah i think that there's a lot of like on a larger scale like those were taken from places that had reputable information whereas i can imagine AI taking stuff from Reddit has a lot of posts that are completely off base added into that. And I would trust it even less than I trust Google's algorithm.
[SPEAKER_00] So great. I mean, it's so it's so fascinating, right? Because I think that on Reddit, people don't always say what they mean. Exactly. Yeah. And, you know, when you're summarizing earnest information where everything has its, you know, more or less unambiguous meaning. I mean, that's great. That's a big stipulation. But on Reddit, there's so many layers of irony. Yeah. And people with multiple intentions, as you noted earlier, ulterior motives, intention for reactions. I think it's a really interesting point. I mean, do you find that reading Reddit as you do, you develop a taste for those ironies and for those ways of, I think, speaking and writing that generative AI could never be able to summarize or interpret?
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, I do hesitate to say that they would never be able to interpret it. It is difficult, right? Because I don't know how this large language model is being trained. But like, there are so many conventions that we even touched on earlier that Reddit has created, like even the abbreviations for like OP and like stuff like that, that I believe that maybe large language models could break down, but could also be confused by like, I don't think. models such as chat gpt that are trained on more generalized sets uh would be able to really interpret like even like the sarcasm that you're talking about and like uh there are many examples of redditors being sarcastic that are enjoyable for us to read like someone in the comments especially but If a AI misinterprets that and is giving an answer based on a sarcastic comment, we could be in some big trouble for people saying just, you know, clean your PC by dumping it in water rather, you know, sarcastically. Whereas an AI would treat that as fact and give it. But I don't know how they're training this. So maybe they found some magical workaround to sarcasm. I
[SPEAKER_00] think it's on their to -do list. But yeah, I think that's a fascinating point. I, yeah, looking, we're at 345. I just wanted to note that because I'm really interested in how students write as if they speak in these spaces too, as a kind of digital morality. People to use the long vowels, stretch things out, these caps. And, you know, I think that for really common posters, I'm going to try to lean into that with interview. But you've just given me really amazing groundwork, Nate. So I just want to thank you for that a thousand times over. I'm
[SPEAKER_01] really glad. This was a really fun conversation. And I can't wait to see where your research goes. Yeah, we might have to look back. We'll bookend it. Yeah, I would
[SPEAKER_00] love that. Get you another $20 Visa gift card. They don't fund us enough at CUNY. But thanks again, Nate. I really appreciate it. Thank you so
[SPEAKER_01] much.
[SPEAKER_00] Yeah, and have a great week. Have a great break.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah, thank you. You too.
[SPEAKER_00] Okay. I'll be in touch about the gift card. And if anything else occurs to you about Reddit, about Discord, controversies and questions, reach out anytime. And
[SPEAKER_01] if you ever, if you update your questions and have something else you want to pick my brain about, feel free to let me know. And I mean, I would love to just talk about it. So yeah,
[SPEAKER_00] you can come back with a pseudonym.
[SPEAKER_01] Yeah. I'll post about it on Reddit. Yeah. Sounds
[SPEAKER_00] good, Nate.
[SPEAKER_01] Thank you so much.
[SPEAKER_00] Alright, I'll see you later. Bye. Bye.